让我们总结一下讲座的要点。当我们拍摄场景的图像时，这是一个视角
Let's summarize the main points from the lecture. When we take an image of a scene, it's a perspective
投影，深度信息已丢失。
projection, and the depth information has been lost.
人类使用许多技巧或视觉提示来恢复缺失的深度信息。
Human beings use a number of tricks or visual cues to reinstate that missing depth information.
我们使用的提示取决于环境和距离。它在我们的范围内吗？
The cue that we use depend on the circumstance and also on the distance. Is it within our
个人空间还是走向地平线？
personal space or is it out towards the horizon?
我们使用的一种特别重要的技术，以及许多其他动物也是如此
A particularly important technique that we use, and so do many other animals, also it
将被机器人使用是一种称为双目视差的技术。这依赖于
will be used by robots is a technique called binocular disparity. And that relies on the
从不同的有利位置拍摄的同一场景的图像之间的细微变化。
small subtle changes between images of the same scene taken from different vantage point.
这是一个立体图像对的例子，我们可以看到左手图像和
Here's an example of a stereo image pair and we can see between the left hand image and
右手图像与我们用左眼和右眼看到的相对应
the right hand image to correspond to what we would see with our left eye and our right
眼睛。一般来说，这两个场景看起来非常相似，但如果我们在那里看得更仔细
eye. In general these two scenes look very similar, but if we look more carefully there
它们之间存在一些微妙但重要的差异，这是微妙的差异
is some subtle but important differences between them, and it's these small subtle differences
这允许提取有关这个世界三维结构的信息。
that allows to extract information about this three dimensional structure of the world.
就像我们有两只眼睛一样，我们可以制造这种紧凑型装配的立体相机
Just as we have two eyes, we can build this stereo camera which is a compact assembly
它实际上包含两个独立的摄像头和已知的pi距离。一个重要的
that contains effectively two independent cameras and known distance of pi. An important
立体视觉中的概念是不一致的。如果我们在左图中识别出一个点并找到
concept in stereovision is disparity. If we identify a point in the left image and find
右图中的相同点看​​起来有点偏向左侧，
the same point in the right image it will appear to have shifted somewhat to the left,
而左移我们称之为差距。
and that leftward shift we refer to as disparity.
重要的是，差异是距离的函数。所以对于一个靠近我们的物体，那里
Importantly, disparity is a function of distance. So for an object that's close to us, there
是一个很大的左移，一个很大的差距，在那里很远的地方有一个
is a large leftward shift, a large disparity, where something that's far away has got a
差距较小。
smaller disparity.
因此，如果我们可以产生差异，那么使用立体视觉的几何，我们可以联系起来
So if we can make the disparity, then using the geometry of stereovision, we can relate
与物体距离的差异。使用这两个图像来计算差异，和
the disparity to the distance to the object. Use the two images to compute disparity, and
从那，然后我可以计算Z.
from that, then I can compute Z.
计算差异并非微不足道。对于左手图像中的每个像素，我取一个正方形
Computing disparity is not trivial. For every pixel in the left hand image, I take a square
围绕它的像素窗口，用于搜索右侧相同的像素图案
window of pixels surrounding it within search for that same pattern of pixels in the right
手形图像，这涉及进行大量的图像比较。这是模板匹配
hand image, and that involves making a lot of image comparisons. It's the template-matching
我们之前看过的问题。
problem that we looked at earlier.
因此，给定场景的左图像和右图像，我可以计算每个像素，
So given a left image and a right image of a scene, I can compute at every single pixel,
视差，我可以将其显示为视差图像或视差图
the disparity, and I can display that as a disparity image or a disparity map, and in
一个视差图，如果它们在附近就会很亮，如果它们更远，它们会变暗
a disparity map, things are bright if they're near and they are darker if they are further
远。相反的是，如果我有一个立体声对，两个图像从略有不同
away. The converse is that if I have a stereo pair, two images taken from slightly different
观点，如果我可以将这些图像呈现给我的左眼和右眼，我会有一个非常的
viewpoints, if I could present those images to my left and right eye, I will have a very
生动的场景三维感，非常非常强烈的深度感。
vivid sense of the three dimensionality of the scene, a very, very strong sense of depth.
人类长期以来一直对3D视觉的想法非常着迷
Human beings have been fascinated with the idea of 3D vision for a long, long time, and
我们讨论了一系列可以执行此功能的技术。
we discussed an array of technologies, which can perform this function.